- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[jazzy suspenseful music]
【爵士悬疑音乐】
*
[dramatic jazzy
flourish]
[戏剧爵士乐
蓬勃发展]
[bbbbbbbb]
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
[brakes screeching]
[overlapping chatter]
[刹车声]
[重叠的喋喋不休]
- Ah!
- Oh!
- 啊！
- 哦！
I suggested having this lesson
in the cemetery
我建议上这堂课
在墓地里
because I thought you
couldn't kill anyone here.
因为我以为你
这里无法杀死任何人。
But now I'm afraid
you're disturbing the dead!
但现在我害怕
你扰乱了死者！
[engine revs]
[发动机转速]
[splotch]
[gasps] Before they bury me,
[斑点]
[喘息]在他们埋葬我之前，
get me to a pay phone.
带我去公用电话。
[muffled cries]
[低沉的哭声]
I need to call
another instructor for you.
我需要打电话
另一位教练为您服务。
I just...can't...
take it anymore!
我只是……不能……
别再这样了！
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
[Mrs. Puff whimpering]
[太太。噗噗呜咽]
both: Aah! Ah! Uhh!
两人：啊啊！啊!呃！
- Huh? You stopped in
front of the prison?
- 啊？你停在
监狱前面？
Never mind! Any place is better
than in this boat with you!
没关系！任何地方都比较好
胜过和你一起在这条船上！
[muttering, whimpering]
[低语，呜咽]
[alarms blaring]
[overlapping shouting]
[警报响起]
[重叠的喊叫]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- What are ya waiting for?
Step on it!
- 你还在等什么？
踩它！
- You must be the new
driving instructor.
- 你一定是新来的
驾驶教练。
[alarms continue blaring]
[shouting continues]
[警报继续响起]
[喊叫声继续]
Student driver.
That's me.
学生司机。
这就是我。
I just don't take
a bad picture, do I?
我只是不接受
一张糟糕的照片，是吗？
- Uh, yeah, yeah, sure.
- 呃，是的，是的，当然。
I'm your new
driving instructor.
我是你的新人
驾驶教练。
- Great! Look at how I can
tune the radio.
- 伟大的！看看我怎样才能
调收音机。
[static]
[静止的]
- Breaking News!
both: Huh?
- 突发新闻！
两人：啊？
- Notorious criminal
Sticky Fins Whiting
- 臭名昭著的罪犯
粘鳍鳕鱼
has just escaped from prison.
刚刚越狱。
- Very good
radio tuning skills.
- 非常好
无线电调谐技巧。
Now,
drive as fast as you can!
现在，
尽可能快地开车！
[alarms continue blaring]
[警报继续响起]
- Stop! SpongeBob!
- 停止！海绵宝宝！
Come back!
回来！
[gasps] I can't believe
I said that!
[喘气]我不敢相信
我说过了！
[engine revs, brakes squeal]
[发动机转速、刹车尖叫声]
- Sticky Fins,
where are you?
- 粘鳍，
你在哪里？
I can't be that late.
我不能这么晚。
- Follow that sponge!
- 跟着那块海绵！
- You ain't Sticky Fins.
- 你不是粘鳍。
- And you ain't
a chocolate cake!
- 而你不是
巧克力蛋糕！
Now, step on it!
现在，踩吧！
- Yes, ma'am!
Dorsal Dan at your service!
- 是的，女士！
多萨尔丹竭诚为您服务！
[police alarms blaring]
[wheels screeching]
[警察警报响起]
[车轮吱吱作响]
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
- [grunts]
Oh! Oh!
- [咕哝]
哦！哦！
Crater-face! We're being
followed. Lose that tail!
火山口脸！我们正在
紧随其后。失去那条尾巴！
- I thought it'd made me
look cool.
- 我以为这让我
看起来很酷。
Guess not.
猜猜不是。
- Not that tail!
The cops behind us!
- 不是那条尾巴！
警察就在我们身后！
Drive crazy!
开车疯了！
- Ohhhhhh, that I can do!
- 哦哦哦，我能做到！
[clattering]
[咔哒声]
[pop]
[流行音乐]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[creak, pop]
Yah-ha-ha-ha!
[嘎吱声，流行声]
啊哈哈哈哈！
Oh, yeah!
哦，是啊！
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
*
- Wow! He's driving
like a psycho!
- 哇！他正在开车
像个神经病！
Who taught him
how to drive?
谁教他的
怎么开车？
- [nervous giggle]
- [紧张的咯咯笑]
- [sucking sounds]
Good baby?
- [吸吮声音]
好宝贝吗？
- Waaaaaahhhhh!
- 哇啊啊啊啊！
*
- Gosh!
[sputtering]
- 天哪！
[溅射]
- [British accent] I say,
how's my automobiling?
- [英国口音] 我说，
我的汽车怎么样？
- [British accent]
Simply smashing.
- [英国口音]
简直就是粉碎。
[normal voice] You're simply
smashing into things!
[正常声音] 你简直就是
撞到东西！
[low chatter]
[低声说话]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
Let's see what's on the menu!
让我们看看菜单上有什么！
Oh! I'll take those.
哦！我会接受那些。
all: Hmm?
全体：嗯？
[Sticky Fingers grunts]
[粘手指咕哝]
[light music]
[轻音乐]
*
- Oh! Oh-ohhh!
- 哦！噢噢噢！
- Excuse me sir, I'm in the
middle of a driving lesson.
- 对不起先生，我在
驾驶课中间。
- Aah!
- 啊啊！
- Look out, you maniac!
- 小心，你这个疯子！
[tires squeal]
[bang]
[轮胎吱吱声]
[砰]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- You're going the wrong way!
Turn this thing around!
- 你走错路了！
把这件事扭转过来！
- You got it!
Turning around!
- 你明白了！
转身！
[drivers screaming]
[司机尖叫]
- Oh, you're a great instructor!
What now?
- 哦，你是一位很棒的教练！
现在怎么办？
- Just...go with the flow.
- 只是...随波逐流。
[light, suspenseful music]
【轻快、悬疑的音乐】
- Looks like they shook us.
Don't worry, we'll find them.
- 看起来他们震撼了我们。
别担心，我们会找到他们的。
- They'll probably revoke my
teacher's license for this.
- 他们可能会撤销我的
教师执照。
- Hey, I'm a teacher too!
I teach all kinds of things.
- 嘿，我也是老师！
我教各种各样的东西。
Safe cracking,
burglary, getaway driving.
安全破解，
盗窃、驾车逃逸。
- [giggles] I did notice
you're a very good driver.
- [咯咯笑]我确实注意到了
你是一个非常好的司机。
- Ha ha, you ain't such a bad
passenger yourself.
- 哈哈，你没那么坏
乘客自己。
[clicks tongue]
- [giggles] Oh, my!
[咔嚓舌头]
- [咯咯笑]哦，天哪！
[dramatic chords]
[戏剧和弦]
- Here's your next test.
Follow me.
- 这是你的下一个测试。
跟我来。
Distracted drivers
are dangerous.
分心的司机
很危险。
I want you to distract that
salesman in the store.
我想让你分散注意力
商店里的推销员。
- I don't understand how this is
gonna help with my driving.
- 我不明白这是怎么回事
会帮助我开车。
- It's, uh...
abstract thinking.
- 这是，呃...
抽象思维。
- Hey, I've heard of that!
- 嘿，我听说过！
- Welcome!
- 欢迎！
- Distract with the abstract.
- 用抽象来分散注意力。
[snaps]
[快照]
[making silly noises]
[发出愚蠢的声音]
- Hey, shapes and noises!
I love it!
- 嘿，形状和声音！
我喜欢它！
[SpongeBob continues
making noises]
[海绵宝宝继续
发出声音]
- [chuckling]
- [轻笑]
[chuckling]
[noises continue]
[轻笑]
[噪音继续]
[beep beep]
[嘟嘟]
[suspenseful jazzy music]
【悬疑的爵士音乐】
- What's the next lesson?
- 下一课是什么？
- The nearest
electronics store.
- 最近的
电子产品商店。
- Oh, you really know how to
challenge a guy.
- 哦，你真的知道怎么做
挑战一个人。
[police sirens wailing]
[警笛鸣响]
- Help! Help!
I've been robbed!
- 帮助！帮助！
我被抢了！
- I've shopped in that place
before,
- 我在那个地方购物过
之前，
and I've been robbed too.
而且我也被抢劫了。
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
- What now, beautiful?
- I wouldn't mind
- 现在怎么办，美丽？
- 我不介意
seeing you navigate
a four-way stop.
看到你导航
四路停靠站。
- Romance always has
the right of way.
- 浪漫总是有的
通行权。
- Oh, my!
- 哦，天哪！
[engine revving]
[发动机转速]
[light music plays]
[轻音乐响起]
- Ah!
Wha--
- 啊！
世界卫生大会 -
Oop.
哎呀。
[random sounds continue]
[随机声音继续]
Whoa!
哇！
[seat mechanism whining]
[座椅机构发出呜呜声]
[click]
[mechanism whining]
[点击]
[机制哀鸣]
[intense percussive music]
[激烈的打击乐]
*
- I need to launder
these bills--fast!
- 我需要洗衣服
这些账单——快！
- I know just the place!
- 我只知道那个地方！
But first,
let me adjust your seat.
但首先，
让我调整一下你的座位。
- Ooh!
- 哦！
Hey! What's the big idea?
嘿！有什么大创意？
[tires screech]
[轮胎尖叫声]
[SpongeBob laughing,
making noises]
[海绵宝宝笑了，
发出声音]
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
*
- What is wrong with you?
- 你怎么了？
- I think your sponge should be
around here somewhere.
- 我认为你的海绵应该是
就在这附近的某个地方。
- [gasps] I didn't even
feel you slow down.
- [喘气]我什至没有
感觉你放慢了速度。
You've got such a gentle foot
on the pedal.
你的脚如此温柔
在踏板上。
- Gosh. No one's ever said
I had a gentle foot before.
- 天哪。从来没有人说过
我以前的脚很温柔。
- Oh-ho.
- 哦嗬。
Oh! Oh!
哦！哦！
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
[gasps]
[喘气]
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
[horn beeping]
[喇叭声]
- Why's that jerk honking?
- 那个混蛋为什么按喇叭？
Go! Drive!
去！驾驶！
- Sorry about
your gentle foot!
- 抱歉
你温柔的脚！
Hi-yah!
- Hey--Owww!
嗨呀！
- 嘿 - 噢！
- Oh!
- 哦！
Ooh, driving Range!
哦，练习场！
- Oh--oh!
- 哦——哦！
*
- How's my driving?
- 我的驾驶技术怎么样？
[bonk]
- Oh!
[棒棒哒]
- 哦！
Doh-doh-doh-doh-doh--
嘟嘟嘟嘟嘟——
- Doh! That kinda hurts,
don't ya think?
- 噢！那个有点疼，
你不觉得吗？
- Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
- 噢！噢！噢！噢！
Pfffffttt!
噗噗噗！
For the love of Neptune,
let's get outta here!
为了海王星的爱，
我们离开这里吧！
- [hums] Uh-huh.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
- [哼哼] 嗯嗯。
嗯嗯，嗯嗯。
Oh!
哦！
[sniffs]
[嗅嗅]
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
- Aah!
Ha ha!
- 啊啊！
哈哈！
[whomp]
[重击]
Ooh!
哦！
Ow!
噢！
*
Oh!
[dinging]
哦！
[叮叮]
[teeth clattering]
[牙齿格格作响]
Ooh--ow!
[sobbing]
噢——噢！
[抽泣]
Aaaaaaaah!
啊啊啊啊！
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
I just wanna know...
我只是想知道...
what'd I ever do
to deserve this?
我曾经做过什么
值得这样吗？
- Would you like to test me
on road signs now?
- 你想考验我吗
现在在路标上吗？
Let's see...
[Sticky Fins continues sobbing]
让我们看看...
[粘鳍继续抽泣]
"Stop,"
“停止，”
"No Left Turn,"
“禁止左转”
and that one over there
that says
那边那个
那说
"Falling Rocks!!!"
“落石！！！”
- Wait, what?
Ooh!
- 等等，什么？
哦！
[wham]
Oof!
[重击]
噢！
[loopy music]
[疯狂的音乐]
[bam]
Whoa!
[嘭]
哇！
- Mm-mm-mm-mm--
- 嗯-毫米-毫米-毫米--
[engine revs]
Oh!
[发动机转速]
哦！
- Aaaaahhhh!
- 啊啊啊！
[sirens wailing]
[警笛哀嚎]
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
*
- [gasps] SpongeBob!
- [喘气]海绵宝宝！
- Mrs. Puff!
- 泡芙夫人！
- Sticky Fins!
- 粘鳍！
- Dorsal Dan!
- 背丹！
Help meeeee!
帮帮我吧！
- Hey, Mrs. Puff!
The new instructor's been
- 嘿，帕夫夫人！
新来的导师是
teaching me so much.
Not as much as you.
教了我很多。
没有你那么多。
But y'know, different things.
但你知道，不同的事情。
- SpongeBob, you gotta keep
your eyes on the road!
- 海绵宝宝，你必须保留
你的眼睛在路上！
- He hasn't taught me
that one yet!
- 他没有教过我
还没那个呢！
Oh!
哦！
- Oh!
- Ah!
- 哦！
- 啊！
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
- Ah! Get me outta here!
- 啊！带我离开这里！
[growling]
[咆哮]
- Aww,
you must be hungry.
- 哇哦，
你一定饿了。
I've got some of
Gary's Snail Snacks.
我有一些
加里的蜗牛零食。
[sirens wailing]
[警笛哀嚎]
- This is the police.
Pull over!
- 这是警察。
套衫！
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
- Right turn!
Make a right turn!
- 右转！
右转！
- Aye, aye, professor!
- 是啊，是啊，教授！
*
[whomp]
[重击]
Yes! I'm back!
是的！我回来了！
[kissing] Thank Neptune!
[亲吻] 感谢海王星！
Don't let me out
ever again!
别让我出去
再来一次！
It's not safe out there!
外面不安全！
Lock me away!
Forever, and ever!
把我锁起来！
永永远远！
all: Huh?
全体：啊？
- Warden, I found this one
pulling up outside the prison.
- 典狱长，我找到了这个
把车停在监狱外面。
- Dorsal Dan! The notorious
getaway driver.
- 背丹！臭名昭著的
逃跑的司机。
Toss him in the clink!
把他扔进叮当声里！
[jazzy musical flourish]
[爵士音乐的蓬勃发展]
- [crying] I'll wait for you,
- [哭泣]我会等你，
my little tenderfoot!
我的小嫩脚！
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- Aaaaaah!
- 啊啊啊！
Whoa!
哇！
Hey, where'd
the new instructor go?
嘿，去哪儿了
新导师去哪了？
Oh, well, I still
have ten minutes left
哦，好吧，我还是
还剩十分钟
on my driving lesson.
在我的驾驶课上。
[singsong]
Oh, Mrs. Puff?
[单曲]
哦，帕夫夫人？
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
Oh...waaaah!
噢...哇啊啊！
I'll confess to anything!
我什么都会坦白！
Throw away the key!
扔掉钥匙！
It's not safe out here!
这里不安全！
Let me in!
让我进去！
all: Drive safely,
and always wear your seat belt!
全部：安全驾驶，
并始终系好安全带！